我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但是我在时间中迷失了
But I became lost in time.
我的朋友们用尽了一切办法才把我救回来
It took everything in my friends' power to bring me back,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
and in doing so our world was opened up to new threats.
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
And I'm the only one fast enough to stop them.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
外面只剩一个公车超能力者了
So, one more bus meta out there.
艾德文·高斯  最好在迪沃之前找到他
Edwin Gauss. You better find him before DeVoe does.
这是智力增强器
This is an intelligence booster.
你说的可是用数量相当大的暗能量
You're talking about intense amounts of dark energy
冲击那个帽子
going right into that cap.
我会帮你完成思考帽
I'm gonna help you finish the Thinking Cap,
-不用暗物质  -行
- without using dark matter. - Fine.
晚上好  威尔斯博士
Good evening, Dr. Wells. How can I be of service?
你好  吉迪恩
Hello, Gideon.
405  市区线路
老牌中城交通管理局的405路公车
Good old CCTA, bus number 405,
我被赋予这个有史以来最棒超能力的地方
where I was gifted with pretty much the best powers ever.
要不是这个老姑娘
If it wasn't for this old girl,
我上厕所时
I'd still have to leave the couch
还得离开沙发呢
when I need to use the bathroom,
因为我可以
you know, because I can--
对  我知道
Yes, I know.
这可能是我们在迪沃
All right, this might be our last chance
抓住最后那个公车超能力者之前
to find any clues on the final bus meta
找到他的线索的最后机会
before DeVoe catches him.
而且我们知道接下来会发生什么
Yeah, and we know what happens next.
我们对这个超能力者知道多少
What do we know about this meta?
除了他的名字  艾德文·高斯  没了
Other than his name, Edwin Gauss, nothing.
他好像消失了
It's like he disappeared.
所以就需要这个崭新的
Well, that explains the brand new,
嗡嗡叫的闪亮的铁玩意儿
beepy, flashy "Schmience" Thingies.
西斯科设计了这些扫瞄仪
Yeah, Cisco designed these scanners
用来发现暗物质异常
to look for dark matter anomalies,
所以留神所有看起来奇怪的地方
so anything that looks weird, all right?
波纹  涟漪  无论是什么  都记下来
Waves, ripples, whatever, log it.
-我找到了点东西  -什么
- I got something. - What?
我的大胃餐厅打孔卡
My Big Belly punch card.
只差五个就能换一份免费儿童套餐了
I'm only five away from a free kids meal,
要是我能活到用它的那一天
if I even long enough to use it.
别开这种玩笑
Man, don't even joke like that.
我们会早在迪沃找到你之前就抓住迪沃
We're gonna get DeVoe, throw him in The Pipeline,
把他关进管道监狱
long before he gets to you.
对  要是这不管用
Right. If that doesn't work,
我们就用其它办法除掉他
we'll just, uh, take him out the other way.
什么其它办法
What other way?
我们一铲子把他放倒
Eh, we'll put him down with a shovel,
给他一把竖琴和一对翅膀
give him his harp and wings,
送他去天上看他的思考者奶奶
send him to visit Grandma Thinker in the sky.
拉尔夫  你觉得我们会杀了迪沃
Ralph, you think we're gonna kill DeVoe?
你说这话的感觉
The way that you're saying that
让我觉得我应该说不
makes me think I'm supposed to say no.
我教过你当英雄的很多事
I've taught you a lot about being a hero, right?
你准备好听可能是最重要的一课了吗
You ready for what's probably the most important lesson?
我们永远没必要杀人
We never have to kill.
对于有我们这样的能力的人
For people with our abilities,
总有其它办法
there's just always another way.
你明白吗
You understand?
艾伦  你使我的生命完整了
Allen, you complete me.
-抱一下  兄弟  拜托  -算了
- Bring it in, man. Come on. - Uh, I'm good.
就一下  抱我一下  拜托
Just a little bit. Give me some, come on.
这是什么
What's this?
等等
Wait a second...
我跟坐这里的人说过话
I talked to guy who was sitting there.
我记得因为我付了他的车钱
I remember, 'cause I paid his fare.
我可能把钱包放在其它裤子里了
I think I may have left my wallet in my other pants.
兄弟  你要么付车钱
Look, buddy, you either pay the fare
要么滚下去
or you hit the sidewalk.
公车司机先生
Mr. Bus driver dude,
允许我为他付钱
allow me to pay his fare.
我们有什么资格决定
Who are we to be the gatekeepers
这位旅行者应该走哪条路呢
of whatever path this fellow traveler is on?
坐吧
Have a seat.
谢谢
Thanks.
向你致敬  兄弟
Oh, namaste, hermano.
在公车后面向你致敬
Namaste in the back of the bus.
好玩的胖兄弟
Funny fat dude.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
他的暗物质残留看起来好像他上一秒还在这里
His residual dark matter reads as if he was here one second,
下一秒就不见了
and the next, vanished.
是哈里
It's Harry.
他想让我们回到尖端科研实验室
He wants us back at S.T.A.R. Labs.
说他有重要的东西给大家看
Says he has something important to show everyone.
我们现在也有
Well...now so do we.
走吧
Yeah. All right, come on.
闪 电 侠
第四季
第十八集
这就是大新闻
That's the big news?
你在社区大学上了雕塑课
You're taking a sculpture class at the community college?
这不是艺术  这是科学
It's not art. It's science!
而且
And as such...
这是能帮助我们打败迪沃的
it is the thing that is gonna help us defeat...
科学
DeVoe.
如果你们愿意  回忆一下我们见过
Recall, if you will, the one thing
或者听过唯一一样
that we've seen-- nay, heard--
真正伤害迪沃的东西
that can actually harm DeVoe.
伊兹·鲍温的声波能力
Izzy Bowin's soundwave powers.
伊兹被迪沃杀了
Well, Izzy was killed by DeVoe,
不管她有过什么能力现在都在他手里了
so whatever powers she had is in his hands now.
现在  乔
And now, Joe...
这能力是我们的
they're in ours.
看着这个
Watch this.
要是你们珍惜自己的
Actually, maybe you should...
内脏器官的话  也许应该后撤几步
take a couple steps back if you value your internal organs.
我知道这什么感觉
I know how that feels.
一击击倒思考者
One strike incapacitates The Thinker.
再击  世上没有思考者
Two strikes, no more Thinker.
我管它叫声之权杖
I call it a Sonic Scepter.
为押韵加一分
Points for alliteration.
基本上就是个大号音叉
Basically just a big tuning fork.
天哪
My goodness.
这不是一把普通的音叉
Well, like, I mean, it's not just any tuning fork.
这可能是多元宇宙中最强大的音叉
This might be the most powerful tuning fork in the multiverse.
你肯定用激光将它加工到纳米级别了
You must've laser-shaved this thing down to the nanometer.
实际上加工到了埃米级别
Shaved it right down to the last angstrom, as a matter of fact.
对我和我的思考帽来说不过是小把戏
Child's play for me and my Thinking Cap.
声之权杖模仿了伊兹·鲍温的声音频率
The Sonic Scepter mimics Izzy Bowin's sonic frequencies,
让我们可以穿破
so we can penetrate
此前无法穿透的迪沃的力场
a heretofore impenetrable force field of DeVoe.
最棒的是
And here's the best part.
因为这里没有什么技术含量
Because there's no tech involved--
-它防基尔戈  -对  -不错
- It's Kilgore-proof. - Yes. -Nice
我们现在只需要知道
So, now we just need to figure out
迪沃接下来会在哪儿出现
where DeVoe is gonna appear next.
实际上  在你们到这之前
As a matter of fact, before you got here--
我写了个口袋维度预测器子程序
I scripted a subroutine on the pocket dimension predictor,
它会给我们很大优势
and it's gonna give us a massive head start.
迪沃的下一个位置  谢谢
DeVoe's next location, thank you.
昨天你还说这是不可能的
Yesterday, I thought you said that wasn't possible.
对  斯诺  我昨天是说了
That's right, Snow, I did say that yesterday,
但今天  是新的一天
but today...is a new day.
我有一百万个新点子
I've got a million new ideas.
帽子和我  我们
The cap and I, we're----
火力全开
firing on all cylinders.
向上  向前
Onward and upward.
开始干吧
Okay, let's get to it.
西斯科  你能把哈里的算法完善做成预测器吗
Cisco, can you integrate Harry's algorithm into the predictor?
可以
Can do.
哈里真是很喜欢那顶思考帽
Harry's really loving that Thinking Cap, huh?
天哪  它就像是他最好的朋友
Oh, my God. It's like the best friend he never had.
他去哪都戴着这个东西
I mean, he wears this thing everywhere.
我确定我看到过他戴着它从浴室出来
I'm pretty sure I saw him step out of the shower with it.
我想知道
I want to know what kinda problem
他在那里需要解决什么问题
he was trying to solve in there.
不
Nope.
不  我不想知道
Nope, I--I don't wanna know.
你在研究什么
What are you working on?
我的大脑  或者说多个大脑
My brain, or brains.
我想我终于发现了激活冰霜杀手
I think I finally figured out the science behind
背后的科学
what activates Killer Frost.
在战斗或逃跑中
So, in fight-or-flight,
肾上腺让身体充满儿茶酚胺
the adrenal glands flood the body with catecholamines,
也就是应激激素
uh, AKA the stress hormone,
猜猜我体内暗物质浓度最高的地方
and guess where the highest concentration of dark matter is
是哪里
in my body?
-肾上腺  -正是
- In your adrenal glands. - Exactly.
所以如果是肾上腺素激活了冰霜杀手
So if adrenaline is what activates Killer Frost,
-那我就只需要  -打一针肾上腺素
- then all I need... - Is a shot of epinephrine.
再也不用哈里和西斯科刺激我
No more Harry and Cisco traumatizing me
让冰霜杀手出现了
to get Killer Frost to show up.
我等不及要告诉她了
I can't wait to tell her.
-等等  你们现在说话了  -算是吧
- Wait, you guys talk now? - Sort of.
我们给对方留言
Uh, we leave each other notes.
多谢新外套
"Thanks for the badass new jacket.
我不小心弄上了血
"I got some blood on it.
不用担心  不是我们的
Don't worry, it's not ours."
我猜她的幽默感需要时间去习惯
I guess her humor is sort of an acquired taste.
口袋维度即将打开
Pocket dimension's about to open.
口袋维度
-是迪沃  -把笔准备好
- It's DeVoe. - Get that pen ready.
准备好
Okay, stay ready.
艾德文·高斯
Edwin Gauss?
什么
What--
各位  这是最后一个公车超能力者
All right, guys, say hello to our last known bus meta,
艾德文·高斯
Edwin Gauss.
我们没有多少关于他的信息
As we know, there's not much on him.
没有大学记录  没有已知住址
No college history, no known addresses.
只有几张旧留言板上的徒步旅行照片
Just a couple of backpacking photos on an old message board.
古老  翻盖手机可以说是古老
Old? Flip phones are old.
这网站还是拨号时代  这算是史前时代
This site is from the age of dial up. Try prehistoric.
没有数字指纹
No digital fingerprint.
这个人的所有东西都和他的过去有关
Everything this guy owns is strapped to his back.
他在成为超能力者之前就落伍了
He was off-grid before he was even a meta.
他的能力让我们找不到他
That, and his powers are the reason we couldn't find him.
为什么公交车上有12个热能信号
And why there were 12 heat signatures on the bus,
包括司机
including the driver.
西斯科  他出现和消失的方式
Cisco, the way he appeared and disappeared...
口袋维度
Pocket dimension.
什么  就像迪沃那样吗
What? Like-- like the DeVoe kind?
不  是艾德文·高斯方式
No, like the Edwin Gauss kind.
你看  口袋维度  就像这个
You see, pocket dimensions, like the one you see here,
每个使用者都不同
are unique to their users.
就像迪沃只能出入他自己的
Just like DeVoe can only enter or exit his,
高斯也受限于他自己的口袋维度
Gauss too is limited to his own pocket dimension.
所以为什么迪沃需要他
So why does DeVoe need him?
迪沃用他的椅子制造了口袋维度
Well, DeVoe uses his chair to create pocket dimensions.
有了艾德文·高斯的能力  他就不需要椅子
If he has Edwin Gauss's powers, he won't need it anymore.
我们得先抓到高斯
Then we need to catch Gauss first.
我们会的
And we will.
我来晚了  在摆弄这顶帽子
Little late. Just tweaking the cap.
听着  找到这个超能力者
Now, listen, locating this meta
并不是我们必须完成的任务
is not a task that we have to accomplish.
为什么  哈里  我来告诉你为什么
Why is that, Harry? I'll tell you why.
因为我们已经做到了
It's because we already... have.
已激活  未激活
这是我们绘制的地图
Yeah, this is the map that we constructed:
显示了整个中城所有
Of all the pocket dimension activity
口袋维度活动
throughout Central City.
但绘制地图时我们认为
Right, but that's when we thought
迪沃拥有所有的口袋维度
all the pocket dimensions belonged to DeVoe.
现在我们不知道他们是迪沃还是高斯的
Now we don't know whether they belong to him or to Gauss.
要想区分它们
And figuring out those distinctions,
抱歉  即使对你来说也是不可能的  哈里
I'm sorry, but that's too big even for your britches, Harry.
我有足够的信心  好吗
My britches are plenty big, okay?
我能做到  看着
I fill my britches. Watch this, okay?
只要追踪到两个车道的标识
By simply tracking the two lanes of identifiers,
交叉对比波动迁移模式
cross-referencing the, uh, fluctuation migration patterns
以及能量应用中的时间位移
and the temporal displacement in the energy app, and...
这就是艾德文·高斯的
I give you Edwin Gauss's
口袋维度活动轨迹
pocket dimension activity.
哈里  哈里太厉害了
"Harry. Harry is amazing."
我们分头行动
Yeah, let's all just split up
在这些地方寻找艾德文·高斯
and search each one for Edwin Gauss.
巴里  你和凯特琳还有拉尔夫一组
Barry, you take Caitlin and Ralph,
我和西斯科还有我爸爸一组
and I'll go with Cisco and my dad.
-哈里  - 我和你一起
- Harry... - I'll go with you.
不  我在想你可以
No, I was thinking that you could just--
你应该留在这守着
you would stay here and hold down the fort.
好  我去调试一下思考帽
Okay, I'll tweak the cap.
警探  你不去找高斯吗
Detective, are you-- are you not going after Gauss?
我正要去
I'm on my way out.
我就是来看看我们出发前你还需要什么
I just wanted to see if you needed anything before we left.
我需要  不用了  我很好
If I need--no, I'm good.
你一直拿着那顶思考帽
Holding that Thinking Cap real close.
你永远不知道什么时候会用上它
Well, you never know when you might need it.
是啊  你只有在
Yeah, and you only need it
有关迪沃的问题上才能用到它  对吗
for DeVoe-related problems, right?
关于迪沃的问题  科学问题
DeVoe-related problems, science problems,
怎样做出完美煎蛋卷的问题
making-the-perfect-omelet problems.
你用那顶帽子做煎蛋卷吗
You make omelets with that cap?
是啊  能做出超棒的煎蛋卷
Oh, yeah. Pretty darn good omelet.
我猜也是  介意我借用一下你的帽子吗
I bet. Hey...do you mind if I borrow the cap?
还是不要了  这不是什么好想法
No, I don't think so. Not a good idea.
为什么  看起来很容易用
Why not? It seems pretty easy to use.
警探  这个看起来很好用的东西
Detective, this easy-to-use thing
事实上是一个精妙的科学仪器
is actually a delicate scientific instrument
能直接改变使用者的脑波
that directly alters the brain wave of the user,
所以  我不这样认为
so I don't think so.
- 所以它很危险  -非常危险
- So it's dangerous? - Yeah, it's very dangerous.
你冒着风险用它做早饭
And yet you risk using it to make breakfast?
好吧
All right.
你很厉害  警探  你非常厉害
Okay, you're good, Detective. You're very good.
你经常带那个帽子吗
How much do you wear that cap?
我没有过度使用它  如果你想问这个的话
I'm not overusing it, if that's what you're asking.
过度使用是一个问题  使用成瘾是另一个
Overusing is one way of putting it. Addiction is another.
我没有沉迷
I'm not addicted to--
你的担心很有道理  拉蒙也有过同样的担忧
Your concerns are well-founded. Ramon had the same concerns.
我告诉他  向他保证
I told him, promised him
我不会在思考帽上
I would not use this Thinking Cap...
使用暗物质
with dark matter.
你遵守了这个承诺吗
And that's a promise you kept?
是的
Yes.
好吧  我不是偏执  我
All right, I don't mean to be paranoid. I'm...
只是警察的职业病
Sometimes, it's just hard to turn off the cop brain.
我明白  不用担心
I get it. No worries.
祝你们找到高斯
Good luck finding Gauss.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
我们在哪
Where are we?
看上去像是个嬉皮公社
Looks like some sort of hippie commune.
闻起来也很像
Yeah, smells like one too.
各位  我想我知道迪沃的计划了
Guys, I think I figured out DeVoe's plan.
他打算用狐臭和熏香让我们窒息
He means to suffocate us with BO and incense.
这是我们单子上最后一个
Okay, well, this is the last pocket dimension hotspot
口袋维度热区  你看到高斯了吗
on our list, so just-- do you see Gauss anywhere?
佩花嬉皮士
Unwashed flower child,
见过这个人吗
have you seen this man?
没有
Nope...
我见过属于这个人的灵魂
I've seen the soul that belongs to this man.
他的气息是一场旅行
The dude's aura is a trip.
等等  你认识艾德文·高斯
Wait, so, you know Edwin Gauss?
当然
Sure do.
在这我们叫他折叠人
Round here, we call him... the folded man.
-折叠人  -他在所有地方
- Folded man? - He's everywhere...
但又不在任何地方
and nowhere...
大部分时间  他在这里
but mostly, he's around here.
各位  到了思维旅行的时间了
Time for the reflection hike, everyone!
别忘了控制好你们的灵兽
Don't forget to leash your spirit animals!
现在已经好闻多了
Literally already smells better.
好了  咱们开始找高斯吧
Okay, let's just search for Gauss.
用通讯器保持联系
Uh, stay in touch over the comms.
好  我要驾驭内心灵兽企鹅
Yeah, I will leash my inner-penguin spirit animal
然后去南边
and head south.
小心点
Be careful.
别碰任何人
Don't touch anybody.
记住  如果我们先找到了高斯
Okay, remember, if we find Gauss first,
我们也许能终结迪沃的计划
we might be able to put an end to DeVoe's plans.
-说到终结迪沃...  -我没那么说
- Speaking of ending DeVoe... - Not what I said.
艾伦  我就是说
Allen, I'm just saying,
迪沃每次都走在我们前面
DeVoe's been ahead of us at every turn.
他的后备计划都有后备计划
His backup plans have backup plans.
如果我们有机会能抓住他
On the off chance that we can't capture him,
我们是不是应该不惜一切代价
shouldn't we be willing to do whatever it takes?
我们知道他会
We know that he is.
我会尽一切手段  除了杀了迪沃
I am willing to do whatever it takes, except kill DeVoe.
即便是自我防卫吗
Even in self-defense?
如果你已经开始想了就不是自我防卫
It's not self-defense if you're already thinking about it.
听我说...
Look, I--
我走上过这条路  我知道你很害怕
I've been down this road. I know you're scared.
我知道这想法多有诱惑力
I understand the temptation,
但你一定要相信我说的  还有其他路走
but you have to hear me when I say there's always another way.
我真希望你的是对的  菜鸟
I really hope you're right, rookie.
各位  我找到高斯了
Guys, I got eyes on Gauss!
对于一个非极速者来说他还真快
He's fast for a non-speedster!
冷静点  缉毒的
Easy, narcs. Hey...
-我投降  -我们不是警察
- I give up. - We're not cops.
但是你处境危险  我们是来保护你的
But you are in danger. We're here to protect you.
真直接
Righteous.
如果你们是  那你们带忍者来干什么
Is that why you're--why you brought your ninja buddy?
什么
What?
-凯特琳  -去尖端实验室会面
- Caitlin! - Meet us at S.T.A.R. Labs.
你阻止不了我  德比先生
You can't stop me, Mr. Dibny.
我会打倒所有闪电小队的人
I will cut through all of Team Flash
来获得我想要的
to get what I want.
你确定你没事吗
Are you sure you're okay?
没事  我的伤口在我醒来前
Yeah, I mean, the wound started healing
就开始愈合了
before I even woke up.
咱们回来的时候你冰霜化了一下
You frosted out for a sec when we got here.
-也许帮上了忙  -是啊
- It probably helped. - Yeah.
你不是该休息吗
Hey, uh, shouldn't you rest?
说真的  我没事
Honestly, I'm fine.
如果有什么  也是让我更想抓到迪沃了
If anything, this has just made me more determined to get DeVoe.
我要去帮助西斯科
I'm gonna go help Cisco
做那个口袋维度预测器
with that pocket dimension predictor.
可能会变得更糟
Well, it could've gone worse.
是啊  看情况我们是运气好
Yeah, all things considered, we got pretty lucky.
运气好  你们认真的吗
Yeah. Lucky? Are you two serious?
难道这里只有我注意到了吗
Am I the only one who's paying any attention here?
拉尔夫  任务成功了
Ralph, the mission was successful.
凯特琳没事  艾德文同意呆在管道监狱
Caitlin's okay, and Edwin agreed to stay in The Pipeline.
-艾德文在那里很安全  -安全
- Edwin will be safe in there. - Safe?
因为迪沃从来没有袭击过
Because DeVoe's never successfully attacked metas
在高度戒备设施里的超能力者对吧
in a maximum security facility before.
等下  他已经做过了
Oh, wait, he did exactly that.
-注意点  拉尔夫  -我一直很注意
- Watch it, Ralph. - I have been watching.
注意到迪沃每次都先我们一步
Watching DeVoe ahead of us at every turn,
注意到凯特琳被袭击
watching Caitlin get skewered,
注意到超能力者一个个的倒下
watching the metas drop like flies, one by one,
就因为我们没法救他们
because we can't save them.
而为什么  因为我们无法做出艰难决定
And why? Because we won't make the tough call
一有机会就要结果迪沃
and end DeVoe when we get the chance.
我不会再干这种事了
Look, I'm not doing this again.
好吧  拉尔夫  我明白你的担忧
Okay, Ralph, I get where you're coming from,
但那不是艰难的决定  而是错误的
but that is not the tough call, that is the wrong one.
好吧  尖端实验室夫妇同意
Oh, Mr. And Mrs. S.T.A.R. Labs agree.
我发誓要是我管理这团队...
I swear if I was running this team--
-但不是你  -好了  行了
- But you're not. - Okay, all right.
可以了  我们没时间干这事  好吗
That's enough. We don't have time for this, okay?
我们需要集中注意力到计划上
We need to focus and stick to the game plan.
找到迪沃  用权杖打他
Find DeVoe, hit him with the scepter,
然后把他放到管道监狱里
and put him in The Pipeline.
没人需要死
No one has to die.
一样的计划
Same plan again.
而你还在好奇为什么每次他都先你一步
And you wonder why he's always ahead of us.
私家侦探玛格侬
Yo... Magnum PI.
我挺喜欢这小释放压力房间的  兄弟
I am digging this tiny panic room, bro.
这个就好像是我身体的蛋壳
It's--it's--it's like-like an eggshell for my body...
也就是我灵魂的蛋壳
which is the eggshell for my soul...
也是蕴含了宇宙奥秘...
which contains the universal myste--
品客薯片
--Zesty Ranch.
太好了
Right on.
我看你就像个喜欢吃小点心的
You strike me as a munchies kinda guy.
有罪
Guilty.
等等  等等  不是真有罪
Oh, wait, wait, wait, not actually guilty.
我又没有惹上麻烦
It's not like I'm on anything, you know?
你们说了你们不是警察  对吧
You--you--you guys said you aren't cops, right?
-不是  -太好了
- Nope. - All right.
但似乎我们要遵守的规则比他们多
But apparently we have to follow more rules than they do.
只要是能保证我远离那个邪恶天才家伙
Well, whatever rules protect me from that evil genius dude,
我就会遵守
I shall heed.
他连名字都很诡异
Even his name is creepy.
"沉思者"
"The Ponderer."
是  思考者
It's, uh, Thinker.
是  确实是个思考者
Yeah, sure is a thinker.
让我思考了我的旅程
Makes me think about my journey.
我第一次折叠的时候
Like, first time I folded,
我在一个白色的空间里困了好几天
I was in this white space for, like, days,
然后还有一次  我碰巧进了一个
and then another time, I tumbled down this ramp
充满着蓝光的太空风格房间
in this space agey room with blue lights,
然后有个光头坐在X教授的悬浮椅子上
and there was this bald dude in a Professor X floaty chair,
脑袋里插着一堆管子
with tubes coming out of his noggin,
还有那么一个女的
and there was this--this lady
穿着白色实验室大褂
in a white lab coat,
有着特别性感的口音
with such a hot accent.
等等  等等  艾德文
Wait, wait, wait, Edwin,
你还记得那里其他什么吗  什么都行
do you remember anything else from there? Anything at all?
这很重要
This is important.
我不知道这个细节有没有意义
Well, I don't know if this detail is relevant,
但是他们那里有那种机器人忍者
but, um, they had one of those robot samurai dudes.
你是在迪沃的老巢  这怎么可能
You were in DeVoe's lair. Wait, how can that be?
西斯科说口袋维度
Cisco said that a pocket dimension
只能被它唯一的使用者接触
can only be accessed by its specific user.
其实吧
I mean---you know,
有些地方比其他地方难去
some places are harder to get to than others,
但如果你把自己的思想上升到更高的境界
but if you ascend your mind to a high enough plane--
你就哪里都能去了
you can go anywhere.
而我的大脑已经很高了
And my mind is really high.
艾德文  你能带我们回到那里去吗
Edwin, can you get us back there?
没问题
"Fa sho."
-来吧  -什么
- Come on. - What?
我这里还有呢
I--I--I got more.
不是  我还没吃完呢  还有呢
No, I--I got more, I got more.
我不能再加快速度了  船长
I cannot do it any faster, Captain!
如果我再增加胶水
If I apply anymore hobby glue,
这艘船就会爆炸
this ship is gonna blow!
这胶水还真是不一般
This glue's really something else.
我应该带上口罩的
I should probably wear a respirator.
在哪里
Where is it?
什么在哪里  出口吗
Where's what? The exit?
就在你身后  请吧谢谢
It's right behind you, please and thank you.
我找不到我的思考帽
I can't find my Thinking Cap.
我这里没有  野人船长
I--hey, I don't have it, Captain Caveman!
我从来没说你拿了
I never said you did,
所以你为什么要自愿分享这个信息
so why would you volunteer that information
除非就是你拿的
unless you do have it?
-出去  -我知道这是怎么回事
- Get out. - I know what this is about.
你一开始就不想让我造出来这东西
You never wanted me to build this sucker in the first place,
因为你从来就不想让我比你聪明
'cause you never wanted me to be smarter than you.
这就有意思了  因为我已经比你聪明了
Well, guess what, that's funny, 'cause I already am.
你在说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
我让你...
I want you to--
-你在干什么  -给我帽子
- What the hell are you doing? - Give me my cap!
-什么  -给我帽子
- Hey! What? - Give me my cap!
还给我  那是我的  是我的帽子
Give it to me. It's mine. It's my cap.
-别闹了  -是我的
- Cut it out! - It's mine!
哈里  不是他拿的
Harry! He didn't take it.
我没拿
I didn't take it.
你肯定有问题
You definitely have a problem, man.
-乔  没事的  -别  安静
- Joe, this is fine. - No, uh, be quiet.
听我说
Just listen.
我在亡妻弗朗辛身上看到过这种迹象
I've seen these signs before with my late wife, Francine.
那时候  我没有很快干预
Back then, I didn't intervene so quickly,
因为我告诉自己  我得确定
because I said to myself, I needed to be sure.
但我其实很确定
But I was sure.
我只是不想看到迹象出现在在乎我的人身上
I just didn't wanna see those signs in somebody I cared about.
我不能阻止你不用它
I can't make you stop using this.
那决定在你
That's up to you.
我只想让你好好地审视下
All I will ask is that you take a long, hard look
这东西对你的影响
at what it's doing to you,
以及它让你对待你在乎的人的方式
and how it's making you treat people you care about.
拉蒙
Ramon...
我们是去哪儿来着
Where are we going again?
你要打开一个口袋维度通向迪沃的老巢
You're gonna open up a pocket dimension into DeVoe's lair,
我要一次性了结他
and I'm gonna stop him for good.
不可能
No, you're not.
西斯科在管道监狱入口安装了
Cisco installed motion detectors
运动探测器
in the pipeline intake.
我以为是迪沃来抓埃德温了
I thought it was DeVoe coming for Edwin.
现在我还挺希望是那样
Now I kinda wish it was.
埃德温可以带我去迪沃的巢穴
Edwin can get me into DeVoe's lair.
我可以结束这一切
I can end this.
你让我走就行了
All you have to do is let me go.
我不能让你这么做
I can't let you do that.
我不喜欢参与吵架
Um, listen, I--I don't really do confrontations,
我回我的玻璃笼子行不
so, uh, can I just go back to my glass cage?
我们马上就离开
We're both leaving in a second.
好吧
Okay.
权杖给我
Just give me the scepter.
你知道必要的话我可以自己拿走
You know I can take it away from you if I have to.
是吗
Yeah?
那你得从我身体里拿走了
Well, you're gonna have to take it out of me.
厉害啊
Oh-- Whoa, bro.
我真挺开心留下来看到这一招的
Wow, okay, I'm actually glad I stayed for that.
太牛逼了
That was trippy.
-别这样  -什么
- Don't do this? - Do what?
这样
This?
抱歉  拉尔夫
I'm sorry, Ralph.
休战吧
Olive Branch?
不想和兄弟喝一杯吗
You don't wanna have a drink with your buddy?
这就是你用来称呼一个刚刚
Is that what you call someone who just went all
装逼失败之人的吗
"Thor, son of Odin" on you?
这个送你了
You can take it.
好吧
Yeah.
我知道你担心迪沃
I know you're worried about DeVoe,
担心他会对你做什么
about what he might do to you,
但有一些界限是我们不能跨越的
but there are some lines we can't cross.
你真的一点都不懂  菜鸟
You really don't know as much as you think you do, rookie.
我知道杀了迪沃对你的影响
I know what killing DeVoe would do to you.
你会毁掉所有你做过的事
You would be throwing away everything you've done:
当一个好人  当一个英雄
to become a better man, to become a hero.
你得意识到
You gotta realize that.
你是个笨蛋
You... are a moron.
-拉尔夫  -我不怕迪沃
- Ralph-- - I am not afraid of DeVoe
还有他会对我做什么
and what he might do to me.
我担心他会对你做什么
I am afraid of what he might do to you...
还有爱瑞丝  凯特琳  西斯科
and Iris and Caitlin and Cisco,
乔  哈里  塞西尔
Joe, Harry, Cecile.
迪沃干掉了所有会碍事的人
DeVoe has taken out everyone who's gotten in his way,
而闪电侠小队
and Team Flash...
会一直碍他的事
they will always be in his way.
这一切从来不是为了保护你自己
This was never about protecting yourself.
我明白杀了迪沃意味着抛弃
I know that killing DeVoe would mean throwing away
我为了成为英雄做过的一切
everything I've done to become a hero...
但除了我妈
But aside from my mom,
这个小队是我拥有过的唯一的家人
this team is the only family that I have ever had,
让了让大家安全
and I would throw myself into a furnace
我宁愿赴汤蹈火
to keep them safe.
迪沃不能伤害他们
DeVoe cannot have them.
他们是我的家人
They are mine.
那我们想要的呢
What about what we want?
你可能不在乎失去现在的自己
You may not care about losing who you've become,
但我们在乎
but we do.
我们喜欢英雄拉尔夫
We like hero Ralph.
请别把他从我们身边夺走
Please don't take him away from us.
拉尔夫误入歧途了
Well, Ralph was misguided,
但他的主意有一半可取
but...he had a half-good idea.
-哪一半  -我们用艾德文·高斯的超能力
- Which half? - We use Edwin Gauss's powers
创造出了通往迪沃巢穴的口袋维度
to create a pocket dimension to DeVoe's lair.
对  这就是我担心的那一半
Yep, that's the half I was afraid of.
不会比这个更危险了
It doesn't get more dangerous than this,
如果我们出发  大家需要表决
so if we go, everybody needs to sign off.
你们俩已经带着小队
Look, you two have led this team
历经了各种各样的危险情况
through every danger there is,
所以如果你们觉得这能阻止迪沃
so if you think this will stop DeVoe
夺走更多生命  那...
from claiming any more lives, then...
我们就去抓住这混蛋
let's go get that bastard.
该死  乔  当你
I mean, damn, Joe, when you put it
电影《虎胆龙威》主角
像约翰·麦克莱恩一样说话  我当然入伙
all John McClane like that, of course I'm in.
我入伙
I'm in.
我都不用问冰霜杀手的意见
I don't even need to ask Killer Frost what she votes.
-我们也是  -那说定了
- We're in too. - So it's settled.
今晚  我们拿下思考者
Tonight, we take on The Thinker.
打开吧
Open it.
收到  超速小子
You got it, mega-fast dude.
15分钟后再次打开
Open it again in 15 minutes.
如果我们没有拷着迪沃出来  就关上它
If we don't come out with DeVoe in cuffs, close it.
就别再打开了
Don't open it again.
-没成功  -为什么会
- It didn't work. - Why would it?
声波对全息图可没用
Sound has no effect on a hologram.
如果迪沃不在这儿  那...
If DeVoe's not here, then...
现在  亲爱的
Now, my love...
真正的战斗开始了
the real battle begins.
发生了什么
What's happening?
有人控制了我们的系统  把我们困在这里
Someone's taken over our systems and sealed us in.
尖端科研实验室里和我们同时打开了
A second pocket dimension opened in S.T.A.R. Labs
第二个口袋维度
at the exact same time as ours.
是迪沃
It's DeVoe.
他用第一个开口隐藏了他自己的入口
He used that first opening to conceal his own entrance.
所以我们的感应器没有记录
That's why our sensors didn't register.
这都在他的计划之中
This is all a part of his plan:
机士攻击  我们找到艾德文
the Samuroid attack, us getting Edwin,
利用他攻击迪沃的巢穴
using him to attack DeVoe's lair.
-他想分散我们  -艾德文去哪儿了
- He wanted us divided. - Where did Edwin go?
他被锁在牢房里了  而且我们从表层
He's back locked in his cell, and we got DeVoe's
接收到迪沃的口袋维度能量了
pocket dimension energy coming from the Cortex.
那一定是他椅子所在的地方
That must be where his chair is.
如果我们能到那儿
I mean, if we can get to it,
就可以用它让队伍在一起
we can use it to get our team back.
首先  我们得离开这里
First, we gotta get ourselves out of here.
-哈里  可以解开密码吗  -在试  但太复杂了
- Harry, can you unhack his code? - Trying, but it's too complex.
如果我有量子密匙
If I had my quantum decryption keys,
就可以  但他们现在在西斯科的工作室里
I could do it, but they're stuck in Cisco's workshop.
但我们没有被困在这里
But we're not stuck in here.
你要做什么
What are you gonna do?
这是我让西斯科创造的一个
It's a little worst-case scenario
适用于糟糕状况的方案
that I had Cisco whip up.
后退  后退
Get back. Get back.
哈里  去拿你的装备
Harry, go get your equipment--
我去黑掉电脑
I'll go and hack the computers.
爱瑞丝  去椅子那儿去
Yeah. Iris, get to that chair.
-爸  你不能  -快去
- Dad, you can't-- - Go.
我听到了所有骚动  我就想
I heard all the commotion, and I thought,
如果迪沃在这里  他会去哪儿
"If DeVoe was here, where would he be going?"
对于一个单纯的人  这是很简单的排除法
A simple deduction for a simple man.
但我向你保证  对于我的智力而言
Though I assure you, you are no threat
你根本不成威胁
for an intellect of my magnitude.
真是够了
Please.
和我对战的所有人都比我聪明
Everyone I fight is smarter than me,
但还没有坏人赢过我
but no bad guy has beaten me yet.
我担心一个老朋友
Well, I'm afraid an old friend
会要求再战
requests a rematch.
我真的很讨厌续集
I really hate sequels.
韦斯特·艾伦夫人
Mrs. West Allen,
我一直期待咱们能再见面呢
I was hoping we'd meet again.
你可能很快就要改主意了
You might change your mind about that pretty soon.
你又拿出了那种
Ah...there's that passion
我们在法院聊天时的热情态度
from our chat in the courthouse.
但我记得我可警告过你
But I do remember warning you
这份热情很容易被浇灭的
that it could easily be destroyed.
我也记得你问过我
And I remember you asking me
为了我丈夫我都愿意做什么
what I was willing to do for my husband.
不如我做给你看看
How about I show you?
-吉迪恩  -请讲  威尔斯博士
- Gideon? - Yes, Dr. Wells?
加大注入思考帽中暗物质的剂量
Increase the Thinking Cap's dark matter feed.
更多
More.
警告  即将超过安全阈值
Warning ...Safe zone parameters will be exceeded.
-建议...  -马上注入最大剂量
- Recommended-- - Maximum capacity now!
来啊
Come on.
再近一点  再近一点
Little closer. Little closer.
警告  管道中的拳头可比看起来的要大
Warning ...Fists in Pipeline are larger than they appear.
不
No.
就算你这种没怎么进化的脑子
Even gray matter as unevolved as yours
也能感知到心灵攻击的痛苦
understands the pain of psychic attacks.
你是为我而生的  德比先生
You were born for me, Mr. Dibny,
而现在
and now...
你要为我而死
you will die for me.
那也是你先死
You first!
那是什么
What's that?
用来臭揍你一顿的大音叉
A big old fork to shove up your--
我再敲一次你就死定了
One more strike and you're dead.
这一刻我等了很久了
I have been waiting for this a long time,
就你我两个人
you and me alone,
我就能做那件谁都不愿做的事了
so I can make the hard choice that no one else will.
或许你是愿意付出相应的代价
Perhaps you are willing to do what it takes...
但看起来我的爱...
But it seems my love...
比你的要强烈
is stronger than yours.
滚出我的办公室
Get out of my office.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
-爱瑞丝  -我没事  我没事
- Iris? - I'm okay. I'm okay.
其他人还在外面和迪沃以及一个机士奋战
The others are still out there fighting DeVoe and a Samuroid.
其实  现在只剩下迪沃了
Actually, now it's just DeVoe.
爱瑞丝
Iris?
我没事  我们必须抓住迪沃
I'm okay, we just need to get DeVoe.
打开缺口送我们去找他  我要让他血溅当场
Breach us to him. I'm ready to get blood on this jacket.
因为贼窝里那次爆炸  我打不开缺口了
That blow back in the lair knocked down my breaching.
我会找到他的
I'll find him.
你是不是...
Did you just...
打败了思考者
Beat The Thinker?
没错  我做到了
Yeah, I did.
你被淘汰出局了  小废物
You just got out-thunk, punk.
而你还是一如既往地按计划行事
And I see you went with the same plan, as always.
你还记得我去监狱里看你的时候吗
Do you remember when I visited you in prison?
你说如果我直起腰来
You said that I could have a greater life
就能有更好的生活
if I'd just rise up.
我准备好过那样的生活了
Well... I'm ready for that life.
而且这是第一次
And for the first time,
我或许配得上这种生活
I might even deserve it.
是
Yes...
看起来我是被打败了
it appears I have been bested.
不过
However...
要不要听我提个醒
a tip, if I may.
在铐住超能力者之前
Before you cuff a meta,
要确保光的颜色是正确的
make sure the light is the right color.
拉尔夫
Ralph!
贝蒂女士从来都不了解
Ms. Betty never understood
她的能力发挥最大时的强大
the full magnitude of her powers.
你现在所受的重力相当于
You're currently the same gravimetric weight
一辆水泥车  艾伦先生
as a cement truck, Mr. Allen.
这应该足够拖住你  让你眼睁睁看着
That should hold you long enough to bear witness.
拉尔夫  快反抗  好吗  反抗
Ralph! Just fight it, all right? Fight it!
我会来救你的
I'll save you.
你已经救了我  巴里
You already did, Barry.
不  不要
No--no...
不
No!
-拉尔夫  -天啊
- Ralph? - God...
后退
Stand back.
融化
Melt.
所有的训练
All the training,
你们给他上的所有课程
all the lessons you taught Mr. Dibny
帮助德比先生发挥出了最大潜力
to help him reach his full potential,
这具躯体将是世上最好的礼物
this body will be the greatest gift of all.
谢谢你  艾伦先生
Thank you, Mr. Allen.
你是个非常出色的老师
You were an excellent teacher.
我们本该救下他们的
We were supposed to save them.
我们尽力了
We tried.
我们失败了
We failed.
我知道这不是我们期待的结局  所以
I know this isn't the ending we were expecting, so...
要是有人想要谈谈...
If anyone wants to talk...
要我跟着他吗
Should I track him down?
不用
No.
我想我知道他要去哪儿
I think I know where he's going.
西斯科
Cisco?
天气预报说有雨  你想帮我一下吗
Uh, weather says rain's coming. Do you mind helping me?
你能去找哈里吗
Can you get Harry?
我觉得我有点不对劲
I think something's wrong with me.
你的生命体征看起来没问题
Well, your vitals seem okay.
血压  呼吸率看起来都很正常
Blood pressure, respiratory rate seems normal as well.
你得再做一遍测试
You're gonna have to run the test again.
我有一种感觉
There was some feeling.
我不知道那是什么  但是
I--I don't know what it was, but...
你碰到了迪沃
You touched DeVoe.
把暗物质扫瞄仪递给我
Hand me the dark matter scanner.
暗物质扫瞄仪
The dark matter scanner...
我去拿吧
I'll get it.
-专心  哈里  -好  专心
- Focus, Harry. - Yeah, focus.
你全身各处都没有暗物质的踪迹
There's no trace of dark matter anywhere on your body.
他肯定是用了融点的能力
He must've used Melting Point's powers
搅乱了你超能力者的基因
to entangle your meta DNA.
-那么冰霜杀手  -消失了
- So, Killer Frost... - Is gone.
还以为会在另一间办公室里找到你
Thought I might find you at the other office.
没有了拉尔夫在一边闪烁其词
Yeah, well, without Ralph being around to dodge rain,
房东收回这里
it's only a matter of time
只是时间问题
before the landlord closes this place up.
我知道这里有些东西
I know there's some things in here
拉尔夫不会想让别人来乱翻的
Ralph wouldn't want anybody finding.
你其实可以跑起来
You know you could just whoosh around
就能快点收拾完了
and you could pack up a lot faster.
是  我知道
Yeah, I know.
-巴里听着  我只是想...  -爱瑞丝
- Barry, look, I just wanted-- - Iris, I...
我知道你是来安慰我的
I know that you're-- you're here for me
好让我能跟你谈谈心  我很爱你这一点
and that I can talk to you, and I love you for that,
但是
but...
现在我只想收拾东西
right now, I just need to pack up.
就这样
That's all.
好吧  也是
Okay, yeah.
我不打扰你了
I'll leave you to it.
我会保护好他们的
I'll keep them safe.
拉尔夫·德比  私家侦探
敬我们非凡的成就
To our overwhelming success.
是的  不止一项成就
Yes, in more ways than one.
-你什么意思  -我的新宿体不光是
- What do you mean? - Not only is my new host body
不会受到我无限扩张的思维的毁坏
immune to the ravages of my ever-expanding mind...
它还有个附加的好处
It also holds an ancillary benefit.
克利福德
Clifford.
没有你我什么都不是
I'm nothing without you...
现在  全部的我
And now, all of me...
又再一次与你在一起了
is with you once more.
但我们必须暂缓庆祝  保持冷静
But we must temper our celebration with conviction.
我们的计划尚未达到高潮
Our plans have yet to reach their apex.
-那是...  -暗物质
- Is that... - Dark matter.
从威尔斯博士给他那顶山寨帽子
Siphoned from the room where Dr. Wells
充能的房间里吸取到的
was charging his counterfeit cap.
如我所料
As I predicted,
他的自大就是他的坟墓
his hubris was his undoing.
而现在
And so, now,
烧毁闪电侠小队的大火
the fire that burns down Team Flash...
将会照亮通往大悟之道的道路
will also light the path to the Enlightenment.